<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Michael's Journal</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://mitchelltribe.xyz/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Personal journal posts</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Keep Trek Running</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;img alt="Futuristic starship gliding past a distant planet with nebula clouds in the background, symbolizing Star Trek's enduring journey and its vision of an attainable future" src="https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/uploads/star_trek_constant_exploration.png" width="600"/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was just watching an old episode of &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: Deep Space Nine&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve always been into Star Trek, every series except &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Next Generation&lt;/em&gt;. I’m not sure why, but I never fully got into that one. The others: &lt;em&gt;The Original Series&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Deep Space Nine&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Voyager&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Enterprise&lt;/em&gt;, and all the movies (except the &lt;em&gt;Next Generation&lt;/em&gt; ones), I loved and eagerly awaited. Whether it was a new film release or the next week’s episode, I was always excited. I never watched &lt;em&gt;Star Trek: The Animated Series&lt;/em&gt; either, even though I own it on DVD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Paramount+/CBS introduced new series: &lt;em&gt;Discovery&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Picard&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Strange New Worlds&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Prodigy&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Lower Decks&lt;/em&gt;. I enjoyed those too, though I hated waiting a week between episodes. I think Netflix got it right: if a show isn’t airing on linear TV, just drop the whole season at once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I even writing this post? Because I think they need to keep a Star Trek series running constantly. And if there’s no show currently airing, there should be a movie in development. The Star Trek universe is expansive enough to support both quality and quantity. There are fans who will keep these stories going. For me, Star Trek represents a future that feels more achievable than the world of Star Wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe we’re close to living in a Star Trek–inspired society technologically. Politically, we may resemble Star Wars more with wannabe emperors, kings, queens, and dictators everywhere or bubbling under the surface.  Still, I prefer the world of Star Trek, it’s more attainable in terms of its technology and processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take Star Wars, for example. It’s supposed to be highly advanced, yet some aspects feel oddly underdeveloped. Star Trek isn’t perfect either, but its depiction of artificial intelligence seems closer to where we are today. I think we should take inspiration from how AI is portrayed in Star Trek. "The Computer" is always just a word away—accessible, helpful, and never intrusive or obstructive like some AI experiences today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#StarTrek #TV #SciFi #entertainment&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaels-journal.pages.dev/keep-trek-running/</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Wed, 16 Jul 2025 20:09:07 -0400</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
