<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Combined RSS Feed</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Write.as blog posts</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Space: 1999 at 50</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/space-1999-at-50?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Alt text: &amp;quot;Graphic celebrating the 50th anniversary of Space: 1999, featuring the number '50' in large white font with the Eagle Transporter spacecraft from the series superimposed over the zero, set against a starry space background. Below the number, the words 'SPACE: 1999 ANNIVERSARY' are written in bold white letters.&amp;quot;" src="https://i.snap.as/0Pmc89lL.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't typically blog about every anniversary or special date. However, I have a soft spot for “this day in history” and similar themes. Yet, some memories from my youth, like Space: 1999, truly resonate with me. Watching it on Saturday afternoons or evenings, I always thought it was an incredible show. I even bought the 30-year complete edition on DVD.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with this classic series, here are the key facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Premiere Date (UK): September 4, 1975&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Premiere Date (US): Aired in syndication starting September 1975, with some stations airing it in prime time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Episode First Aired: November 12, 1977 (varying by region through 1978)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Number of Episodes: 48&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Series (Seasons): 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year One: 24 episodes (1975–1976)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Year Two: 24 episodes (1976–1977)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US Broadcast Notes: The series was syndicated in the US, meaning it aired on various local stations rather than a single national network. Episode order varied widely between regions, sometimes mixing Year One and Year Two randomly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a passionate sci-fi enthusiast, I love series like Star Trek, Star Wars, Space: 1999, Lost in Space in all its forms, and Forbidden Planet with Robby the Robot. These series are woven into the fond memories of my younger days. I've also witnessed many of the futuristic technologies depicted in these shows come to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon a YouTube video recently &lt;iframe allow="autoplay; fullscreen; encrypted-media; picture-in-picture;" allowfullscreen="true" class="embedly-embed" frameborder="0" height="360" scrolling="no" src="//cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FDICMyq-pzhg%3Ffeature%3Doembed%26start%3D10&amp;amp;display_name=YouTube&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DDICMyq-pzhg&amp;amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FDICMyq-pzhg%2Fhqdefault.jpg&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=youtube" title="YouTube embed" width="640"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt; and discovered that it's the 50th anniversary of Space: 1999, one of my all-time favorite sci-fi series. I felt compelled to celebrate this occasion and reflect on its impact on my life. While the show may not hold up perfectly today, with some episodes feeling a bit quirky, I still long for one of their communicators or Eagles for my personal collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy 50th Anniversary, Space: 1999. I'm not sure if any of the original cast are around, but if you are, thanks for the show and the memories. This milestone reminds me that great science fiction doesn't just entertain; it inspires generations and becomes part of who we are. Here's to the show that made us look up at the moon and wonder what could be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/space-1999-at-50</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
