<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Combined RSS Feed</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Write.as blog posts</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Trivial Trials and Tribulations</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/trivial-trials-and-tribulations?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A black and white illustration depicting a middle-aged man with glasses, sitting thoughtfully at a chessboard that spans the width of the image. On the left side of the chessboard are chess pieces mixed with medical and insurance-related documents, pill bottles, and rolls of money, symbolizing health care. On the right side, traditional chess pieces are arranged, suggesting a strategic game or decision-making scenario. The man appears contemplative, possibly weighing his options or decisions." src="http://192.168.1.21:5001/api/uploads/dalle_473fda63f8ab.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Contemplating life's strategic moves amidst a sea of medical bills and insurance forms, the real battle transcends the chessboard.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I have been officially out of Camzyos for over a week. I finally got it after calling the insurance every day for a week and being told something different. It started out that the ECHO hadn't been uploaded to their portal. Message to doctor on MyChart. Sent it to the wrong cardiologist. I have 3: a cardiologist, a HOCM specialist, and an electrophysiologist. So forgive me for picking the wrong one. The message still got to where it needed to go. Didn't matter anyways, as the insurance then found another thing they didn't like on Wednesday. They didn't like the dosage the doctor ordered because they didn't think it needed to be increased because of the ECHO. So they had to reach out to the doctor. Again, another message in MyChart, same thread that I was told I messaged the wrong office. Again, got to where it needed to go. At least they are all looking at the same messages.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally called the Specialty Pharmacy again and finally got to the end this time. This has put me out of pocket for the rest of the year. Got my medicine on Friday. Every month this is an ordeal. I work in the healthcare industry and we really need an overhaul, especially with insurance companies. There is this whole administrative layer upon layer upon layer that drives the cost up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was one thing this past week. I have been stressed for the last couple of weeks. That was one issue of many all trivial to the casual observer. The other is I potentially have jury duty on Tuesday. I won't know for sure until Monday afternoon. If I am not canceled, I have to show up on Tuesday. I hate jury duty. I understand it is a civic duty, but I feel that the jurors are on trial. All the questions they ask, and you are sitting in a room full of strangers and having to listen to their stories and then explain yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the icing on the cake: I added another platform to my blog poster project and it broke my whole system. After getting Write.as working flawlessly, I also had to add security, and that added problems. You'd think the AI would know how to do this. But after a day and a half, I got the program to about 95% and a lot of bugs squashed. So I now have Write.as/Snap.as, Blogger/Cloudflare R2 object storage hooked up. AI seems to be brilliant at times and then stinky at others. I have relied more and more on Claude and have thought about canceling my ChatGPT subscription ever since they released GPT-5. From my perspective, it seems dumber, just like when Google went from Bard to Gemini. I thought Bard was the best until Gemini ruined that for me, and the same for GPT-5. I don't care about the personality. I just want reliable and truthful responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that is an update on my trivial trials this week. Hopefully this next week will be brighter and less stressful, and it will be if they cancel my jury service. I am taking the whole day off Friday because I have another ECHO for this new dose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/trivial-trials-and-tribulations</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mon, 13 Oct 2025 21:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
