<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Combined RSS Feed</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Write.as blog posts</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tracing Roots Lost to War</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/tracing-roots-lost-to-war?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='A vintage collection of documents on a wooden surface, including a Polish passport ("Paszport Rzeczpospolita Polska") with a gold eagle emblem, several aged letters with handwritten text, and a paper labeled "Immigration Service Ellis Island Immigrant Inspection of 1892-1998." The items evoke a historical theme related to immigration and travel.' src="https://i.snap.as/HD43q9So.png"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Echoes of a family’s journey across time and borders.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to blog about this for a while. This will  probably be a long one—and it might even turn into a series of posts  around a central theme.
My mother—more than me, but me too—has always wondered about her mother’s family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Childhood Cut Short&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My grandmother was born in Poland in 1926, before World War II. She was  just 13, almost 14, when Germany invaded. According to my mother, my  grandmother was at school in Kraków when the invasion happened. She was  taken away from her parents, older brother, and sister. The last time  she ever saw them was before going to school that day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just  learned this part while preparing for this post: my grandmother was  taken to a concentration camp and was “in line for a shower.” She was  seen by a German officer, who pulled her out of the line. She was forced to serve as an au pair—but in truth, she was a slave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My  mother told me that, surprisingly, my grandmother was treated well by  the German and his family and was almost certainly saved from death by  that officer. My grandmother never knew why she was chosen out of  everyone in line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all know what “going into the showers”  meant. But I don’t think it was just fate that saved her—I believe it  was divine intervention. If not for that moment, how would my mother be  here today—and, by extension, my brother, sister, and me?
&lt;strong&gt;God has a plan for all of us, and He always makes sure His plans are carried out.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Family Lost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She never reunited with her parents or siblings. That part of her life remains a mystery to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were they killed? Did they survive? Did my great-uncle or great-aunt have  children? Do I have cousins in Poland—in Kraków or somewhere else—even  today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An American Love Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know she met my maternal grandfather during the war—he was an American  soldier—and supposedly fell in love with him. That’s how she came to  America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, by extension, I know almost nothing about  that side of my family. It starts and stops with her. Poland is still  high on my bucket list to visit—maybe someday I’ll find out more. But  for now, it remains a blank page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Marriage Rediscovered&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My mother told me that my grandparents were married three times: twice in  Germany and once in the United States. First, they were married by an  Army chaplain. Then they had a church wedding. Finally, they married  again in the U.S.—probably in West Virginia.
&lt;img alt="A vintage portrait of a smiling bride in her wedding attire. She wears a white gown with a high collar and a delicate cross necklace. Her hair is styled in elegant curls topped with a floral headpiece and a flowing veil. She holds a large bouquet of white flowers, adding a classic touch to her joyful expression." src="https://i.snap.as/OflGrLXa.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Luisa Tekiel in her wedding Dress circa 1947&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language and Loss&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know my grandmother  was illiterate in English. She could speak it and learned to sign her  name, but she couldn’t read at all. When she arrived in the U.S., her  English was limited, and immigration officials didn’t spell her name  correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do know she came through Ellis Island—but with no reliable records, there’s no easy way to trace her family history from  there. That makes it even harder to fill in the blanks.﻿
&lt;img alt="A vintage black and white photo of a smiling woman in a fur coat and a man in military uniform, both on the deck of a ship. The man is partially obscured by the woman who is seated in the foreground. Behind them, part of a naval anti-aircraft gun is visible, suggesting a wartime setting. The ocean and a hazy sky form the backdrop, enhancing the historical feel of the image." src="https://i.snap.as/meAohtjT.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Louise Tekiel aboard the ship to America.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;﻿While researching the name &lt;strong&gt;Tekielowna&lt;/strong&gt;, which appeared on a Bible insert, I found out my grandmother’s real maiden name was &lt;strong&gt;Tekiel&lt;/strong&gt;, not &lt;strong&gt;Tekielowna&lt;/strong&gt;, which had appeared on all her other paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, there was a custom in Poland at the time where unmarried women or girls had “-owna” added to the end of their surnames. That explained the  discrepancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Weight of Unanswered Questions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has always weighed on my mother. She’s always wanted to know about her  cousins, aunts, and uncles—if any are still out there. She feels  unsettled, and maybe even resigned, to never knowing anything about her  mother’s side of the family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my maternal grandfather’s  side, she knows a little more—but not much. They always treated her like an outsider. Either they didn’t like my grandfather, or something else  was going on.
﻿&lt;img alt="A vintage colorized portrait of a young couple; the woman is wearing a dark blouse and a necklace, resting her head on the shoulder of a man who is dressed in a military uniform with a beret and decorated with multiple ribbons on his chest. Both are looking directly at the camera, conveying a serene and affectionate demeanor." src="https://i.snap.as/7vAXgx3D.jpg"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Louise and Joe Kinser, early in their life together.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Story Still Unfolding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never knew either of my grandfathers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My paternal grandfather died when my dad was still a child. My maternal  grandfather was never really in the picture. He and my grandmother  separated and later divorced. And so, another part of the story was lost before it could be passed down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even now, there’s so much I don’t know. But I’m starting to piece things together—one memory, one clue, one discovery at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And maybe that’s where you come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re reading this and you’re from Poland—or have family roots in Kraków or the surrounding area—and the name &lt;strong&gt;Tekiel&lt;/strong&gt; sounds familiar, I’d love to hear from you. Maybe you’ve heard stories  passed down, or maybe your family tree has a missing branch too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This might just be the beginning of something—maybe more stories to come, maybe even some answers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/tracing-roots-lost-to-war</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
