<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Combined RSS Feed</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Write.as blog posts</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">A Week of Exhaustion, Frustration, and Hope</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/a-week-of-exhaustion-frustration-and-hope?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="A man in a maroon polo and khaki shorts sits on a wooden park bench at sunset, reading a newspaper. A tumbler of iced tea, a smartphone, and two e-readers rest on the bench; a curving paved path and green trees glow in warm light" src="https://i.snap.as/111dPxoS.png"/&gt;
&lt;small&gt;Quiet golden-hour read with tea and tech in tow.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My week has been hectic with work and being off Camzyos for over a week now.“Why are you off your Camzyos? I thought it was helping.”Yes, it has helped. I have felt better. I am not energized and still fatigued, but I have been able to do things without feeling like I was going to pass out from exertion. The specialty pharmacy would not fill the prescription without every box checked. My doctor’s office also failed to upload my latest ECHO. The pharmacy never contacted me, simply put the prescription on hold, and left me in the dark. I had to reach out myself to find out what was happening. On Friday the medicine finally shipped. Will I get it today? Who knows. I was told Thursday, then Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also cutting back on my use of hashtags in social media posts. Lately I have gotten trolls and some nasty responses. I do not mind opposite or contrary views, but the tone was uncalled for. Hashtags used to be a good way to find people talking about the same things. Unfortunately, hashtag hijacking has become common, and I do not want to feed that beast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the week closed, I was glad to spend time pondering more relaxing things and holding on to hope that the Supreme Court will keep intact two rulings that struck down parts of Trump’s tariffs. These tariffs have been the largest tax increase in my lifetime and have driven prices higher while keeping inflation stubborn. If the Appeals Court and Trade Court decisions are upheld, the choice will fall to Congress. Either they bail Trump out by raising taxes, or they do nothing. I doubt they want to admit the tariffs were harmful and amounted to tax increases. Inflationary pressure could finally ease, with the side benefit of giving Trump a well-deserved kick in the pants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/a-week-of-exhaustion-frustration-and-hope</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sat, 30 Aug 2025 23:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
