<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Combined RSS Feed</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Write.as blog posts</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Is This the Wake-Up Call We Need?</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/is-this-the-wake-up-call-we-need?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;p&gt;The assassination of Charlie Kirk today is a tragic reminder that political violence is never the solution. It only creates deeper divides and encourages an “us versus them” mentality that is actively harming our society. The proper place to resolve political differences is at the ballot box and through civil debate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This destructive rhetoric and division is not new. It has been encouraged for years and has been festering over time. The current environment reinforces a dangerous dynamic that threatens our democratic institutions. I have said this before, and I will say it again: politics is just one aspect of life, but its current state is consuming our nation. Politicians on both sides have not helped by trying to one-up the other party in order to stay in power, and it is a disservice to the public they serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government employees take an oath to uphold, defend, and protect the Constitution of the United States. Part of that oath means doing what is right for the principles of our republic, not what is right for a specific party. The Constitution was written to allow people to live with representation and dignity. The tragic loss of life, from both public figures and private citizens, should be a wake-up call for everyone to dial back the rhetoric. The nation is like a kettle beginning to whistle loudly. Starting from the President down, we all need to take a collective breath, pause, and step back from the cliff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will inevitably be a call to address the issue of gun violence. While the Second Amendment is a foundational part of our nation, a right to bear arms must be balanced with the need for public safety. Many Americans, regardless of party, agree on common-sense measures like universal background checks and red flag laws. This is not about eliminating all guns, but about preventing them from falling into the wrong hands. Arguments that an outright ban would be ineffective miss the opportunity to find solutions that can save lives without infringing on the rights of law-abiding citizens. Look at England as an example. They have very strict gun laws, yet still struggle with knife crime, showing that banning one type of weapon does not eliminate violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The loss of life is always a tragedy, no matter who the victim is. My hope is that we can finally learn from this moment before more lives are lost and that we all step back from the edge before we all fall off the cliff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/is-this-the-wake-up-call-we-need</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Thu, 11 Sep 2025 02:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
