<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Combined RSS Feed</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Write.as blog posts</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Finally, Great Heart News</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/finally-great-heart-news?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;p&gt;Great news today at my follow-up with my hypertrophic cardiomyopathy specialist. Camzyos is really starting to work. My most recent echo earlier this week was excellent, and so was the heart cath I had in late December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the heart cath showed that Camzyos is working well enough that I do not need to rush into an alcohol ablation or a septal myectomy. If I ever do need an intervention in the future, my doctor said I would be a good candidate for septal alcohol ablation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also told my doctor that, if at all possible, I would prefer to stay on medication and avoid any surgical treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More good news: I will not have to see him or have another echo for six months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I told the doctor I have been feeling great since starting Camzyos. My metoprolol dose was increased last month, and I have been sleeping much better. He said everything seems to have calmed down, and my gradients with exertion have improved greatly. So, no immediate decisions need to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also had a positive conversation with the cardiac interventionist and personally read my echo himself. It looked good, and he is pleased. I told him that I think staying consistent with my medication has helped. Lately, I have not had delays caused by the pharmacy needing certain tests before refilling my prescription, and I have not had any breaks where I was off the medication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means my main job now is simply dealing with the pharmacy and making sure I get my Camzyos on time each month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let's pray it keeps trending in the right direction. I actually feel normal for once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="hashtag" href="https://michaelmitchell.blog/tag:health"&gt;&lt;span&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p-category"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="hashtag" href="https://michaelmitchell.blog/tag:news"&gt;&lt;span&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p-category"&gt;news&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="hashtag" href="https://michaelmitchell.blog/tag:personal"&gt;&lt;span&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p-category"&gt;personal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmitchell.blog/finally-great-heart-news</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sat, 10 Jan 2026 03:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
