<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scribbles Posts</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Posts from Scribbles.page</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Ed Zitron Might Be Right, But I’m Still Using AI Every Day</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/post/ed-zitron-might-be-right-but-i-m-still-using-ai-every-day</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;figure class="attachment attachment--preview flex-col justify-center attachment--png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Person using a laptop at a minimalist desk while a glowing AI assistant hovers nearby, displaying icons for creativity, technology, and design." class="lightbox__image strip-metadata lightbox__image" decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBNkJDQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--ea27f0ab3bac3e08fa25acf8b472094dca2a2eab/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUNHa0NBQVk2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--768aeab7fb7843d85fe5b2b4ba237e06e6ef604f/human-ai-workspace-digital-helper.png" srcset="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBNkJDQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--ea27f0ab3bac3e08fa25acf8b472094dca2a2eab/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUVHa0NBQXc2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--a18847b6c1cccf2736612f487841b9c550593dc1/human-ai-workspace-digital-helper.png 2x"/&gt;
&lt;figcaption class="attachment__caption text-center"&gt;
      AI at your side—just another tool on the desk.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been listening to Ed Zitron and his podcast &lt;em&gt;Better
Offline&lt;/em&gt;. He’s not shy about his views: he believes that most AI
companies are burning through cash and are likely to fail because they
don’t have viable products. I respect his perspective. He clearly
understands the tech industry and sees AI as mostly a kind of “magic
trick”—a system that assembles words in ways that &lt;em&gt;appear&lt;/em&gt;
intelligent, but in reality don’t demonstrate real understanding. That’s
my paraphrase, not his.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for me, I don’t claim to fully understand the business models of
these companies or whether they’re financially sustainable in the long
term. But to be honest, I’m not especially concerned. I’m not investing
in them. The only money I’ve put into this space is my $20 per month
subscription to ChatGPT from OpenAI, and for that amount, I get value in
return.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, AI is a tool. I use it to proofread my blog posts, do light
research, generate feature images, and even help with simple programming
projects on my Raspberry Pi. I also use it to learn new IT skills. It
works well for these tasks, and I understand its limitations. I still
fact-check its outputs where it matters, but I don’t expect
perfection—just usefulness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zitron often focuses on the financials: burn rate, lack of revenue, poor
leadership. I understand that perspective. But as a consumer, I’m less
concerned with whether these companies are profitable and more focused
on whether the tools are useful to me. For $20 a month, I now have
access to editing support, basic IT guidance, image generation, and
other tasks that would have previously required hiring multiple
professionals—something most average people could never afford in the
first place. In that sense, AI hasn’t replaced services the public was
actually using; it has made previously inaccessible services newly
available. That’s a net gain for consumers, not a loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect the industry will consolidate over time. Some companies will
fold, others will adjust their pricing models. But the technology is out
in the world now. You can’t put the genie back in the bottle. If AI
tools eventually become unaffordable for average users, that would be a
real loss. The core promise of AI—at least for consumers—is the
democratization of services and skills that used to be out of reach for
most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the product. Whether it’s profitable yet is someone else’s
problem to solve. I use AI tools in a way that works for me, and I feel
I’m getting my money’s worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, I do agree with Ed Zitron on another key point: many tech
CEOs don’t seem to understand the very technology they’re hyping. They
make contradictory statements, avoid hard questions, and often speak in
buzzword-laden jargon. Meanwhile, the press rarely holds them
accountable or asks for clear, honest explanations—just as we’ve seen in
politics. That’s a broader trend worth worrying about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More broadly, I think we’re drifting into a corporate-oligarchy model of
governance. We’re not there yet, but we’re heading in that direction.
The old saying holds true: the rich are getting richer, the poor are
getting poorer, and the middle class is shrinking. It's happening faster
than most people realize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I wonder if anyone’s asking what happens to the engineers
building these AI systems. At what point do they realize they’re
creating technology that may replace many of their own jobs? And what
if, in response, some begin to embed subtle flaws or
weaknesses—intentional sabotage that’s difficult to detect? It reminds
me of &lt;em&gt;Rogue One&lt;/em&gt;, where Galen Erso secretly builds a fatal flaw
into the Death Star. That Star Wars reference might sound dramatic, but
the point stands: humans build these systems, and humans have motives,
fears, and limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;#AItools #TechPerspective #ConsumerVoices #BetterOffline&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">tag:michaelmusings.com,2005:Post/12762</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sun, 20 Jul 2025 23:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
