<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scribbles Posts</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Posts from Scribbles.page</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Free Streaming TV and Pesky Ads</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/post/free-streaming-tv-and-pesky-ads</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;figure class="attachment attachment--preview flex-col justify-center attachment--png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Black-and-white ink drawing of a man in an armchair watching a vintage TV; rain on the window, lamp glow, single side table holding stacked DVDs, a glass of iced tea with visible cubes, a tablet with streaming icons, and a smartphone" class="lightbox__image strip-metadata lightbox__image" decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBeGhMQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--f067e4db829e89e4fc7b3aedad4fc06333654ffa/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUNHa0NBQVk2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--768aeab7fb7843d85fe5b2b4ba237e06e6ef604f/cozy-living-room-single-side-table-pen-ink.png" srcset="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBeGhMQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--f067e4db829e89e4fc7b3aedad4fc06333654ffa/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUVHa0NBQXc2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--a18847b6c1cccf2736612f487841b9c550593dc1/cozy-living-room-single-side-table-pen-ink.png 2x"/&gt;
&lt;figcaption class="attachment__caption text-center"&gt;
      Rainy night comfort: vintage TV, streaming apps, and a glass of iced tea
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;If you’ve been following or reading my blog over the years (and
many people probably haven’t), you know I like watching TV. I love Star
Trek (all the iterations except TNG) and older shows like &lt;em&gt;Green
Acres&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;All in the Family&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;MASH&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bunker’s
Place&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Barney Miller&lt;/em&gt;, and British series like &lt;em&gt;Doc
Martin&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Grantchester&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Foyle’s War&lt;/em&gt;, along with
many others. I really enjoy how new streaming services like Amazon
(MGM), Pluto TV, Tubi TV, and Plex make so much of this content
available for free. One of my favorite features is when they turn a show
into its own channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past weekend it rained the entire time. I watched one movie, but
before and after that I mostly had either the Pluto TV &lt;em&gt;Star Trek:
Voyager&lt;/em&gt; channel or the Amazon MGM &lt;em&gt;Green Acres&lt;/em&gt; channel on,
unless I was watching regular TV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also own a lot of DVDs of these shows. I like having the discs because
cancel culture seems to get worse every year, and I want to make sure I
can always watch the things I enjoy. I’ve been working on digitizing
everything I own for archival and backup purposes, though the TV and
movie industry doesn’t make that easy (that’s a topic for another post).
Normally I don’t care for free streaming services because, like regular
TV, they include ads. But since I’m not paying for them, I tolerate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One category of ads I’ve noticed a lot on Pluto TV is casino-style slot
apps. They are heavily promoted. If an adult wants to play those games,
that’s their choice, but I’m not sure it’s a good idea to make those ads
so visible to impressionable young people, especially young males. It
feels like the ads are designed to make gambling seem fun and easy to
start. I’m not trying to preach, since I occasionally play the lottery,
which is gambling too. But I don’t see lottery ads every single
commercial break. The slot ads, on the other hand, sometimes run two at
a time, and they even frame the story as if young men are already hooked
and stealing to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s just my two cents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">tag:michaelmusings.com,2005:Post/13168</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:39:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
