<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scribbles Posts</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Posts from Scribbles.page</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Divorce maybe in the Future with Microsoft and Windows</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/post/divorce-maybe-in-the-future-with-microsoft-and-windows</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;figure class="attachment attachment--preview flex-col justify-center attachment--png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="A visionary stands at the crossroads of innovation, contemplating the expansive network that may redefine the future of technology." class="lightbox__image strip-metadata lightbox__image" decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBNWhwQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--819c3d1186e6dd12eaaebba911127a8b193282f4/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUNHa0NBQVk2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--768aeab7fb7843d85fe5b2b4ba237e06e6ef604f/blog_post_image_dmw.png"/&gt;
&lt;figcaption class="attachment__caption text-center"&gt;
      A visionary stands at the crossroads of innovation, contemplating the expansive network that may redefine the future of technology.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a loyal Microsoft Windows customer since I've owned a PC and MS-DOS was a thing. I went to the events they had for major OS releases with my Dad. We both went to see the exciting things that happened when they used to stream them at movie theaters. I was there for the launch of Windows 95.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is my opinion that Microsoft has totally lost its way with regards to the consumer and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, this is a rant, and I believe it may be too late for Microsoft and Windows with consumers. I know I am not a very techie person, but I believe that Windows is getting too messy in a lot of areas like advertisements everywhere, sloppy code, updates that seem like beta versions, telemetry, privacy concerns, and just all around not caring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I follow &lt;a href="https://www.thurrott.com"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paul Thurrott&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BuH0BiWeG3U&amp;amp;t=2176s"&gt;^1&lt;/a&gt; and Dave Plummer from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@DavesGarage"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dave's Garage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;strong&gt; YouTube channel &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oTpA5jt1g60"&gt;^2&lt;/a&gt;, and they both have different takes on what should happen to get Windows back on top. I can see both points and agree with both points. But I also agree with Paul Thurrott that Microsoft will not bend unless there is a clear reason to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is keeping me on Windows? If it weren't for the games I have, and I do mean lots of games, I would probably be on a different platform. Other than that, I do use it for work and I like the easy installation of programs and it looks good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where it gets interesting. I am getting more and more into Linux and have been thinking about MacOS lately (yikes, I know. I have an iPad and don't really care for the OS on that or for Apple). Thanks to Windows' missteps and bad practices and taking advantage of the consumer (though Apple excels in this area), Linux is catching up and there may be a solution for my gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google could step in here, but they are making a lot of bone-headed moves too and are getting where they only want to chase Enterprise/Business. Everyone always underestimates the consumer, and the consumer is already leery of Google because they kill off most of their products just as consumers are right in the middle of falling in love with them and have major privacy concerns. Google is the Hoover vacuum cleaner of the internet. Their old motto of "Don't be evil" is being replaced. They are like the opposite of the character from the Despicable Me movies, going from good to evil instead of evil to good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us back to Microsoft. Microsoft kills off a lot too, not to the frequency of Google, but still a lot. I'll give Apple some credit: they generally support their products longer, even if they're not massive successes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft may derive most of their revenue from the Enterprise/business side, but consumers will always keep you in the black if you have a good product. You just might not be a trillion dollar company in the process, but you'll be profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I'm learning Linux and waiting for it to become even more consumer friendly through distributions like ZorinOS and CasaOS, or maybe going the direction like Omarchy. I'm continuing to self-host and use AI to build custom applications via Python. I'm hoping SteamOS gets that missing piece so developers support it and we consumers can finally break free from these trillion dollar companies. My goal is to be down to one cloud service provider in five years. The only reason I have multiple now is family obligations, since my parents are in their 70s and I manage everything for them digitally. But whenever I can, I'm moving off these platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's where I'm heading. I don't know if Microsoft will ever earn my loyalty back. Google won't either. Apple has never had my trust and I still distrust their whole ecosystem, though I'm a realist and do use some of their services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/b&gt;]  &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BuH0BiWeG3U&amp;amp;t=2176s"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BuH0BiWeG3U&amp;amp;t=2176s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[&lt;b&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/b&gt;]  &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oTpA5jt1g60"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oTpA5jt1g60&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">tag:michaelmusings.com,2005:Post/14326</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">n8n</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
