<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scribbles Posts</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Posts from Scribbles.page</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">🎥 Watched Superman (2025)</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/post/watched-superman-2025</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;p&gt;⚠️ &lt;strong&gt;SPOILER WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; FULL SPOILERS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Promotional poster featuring a male actor in a Superman costume, standing confidently with arms crossed. The background glows with vibrant blue and red light rays, highlighting the iconic Superman logo on his chest. The text 'DC Studios Superman' is displayed at the bottom." src="https://media.mitchelltribe.xyz/images/2025/12/2821f393_tmdb_102cc9c05fe1.jpg" title="Promotional poster featuring a male actor in a Superman costume, standing confidently with arms crossed. The background glows with vibrant blue and red light rays, highlighting the iconic Superman logo on his chest. The text 'DC Studios Superman' is displayed at the bottom."/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Superman returns in a radiant display of heroism and hope, ready to light up the skies and our hearts in 2025.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Rating:&lt;/strong&gt; ⭐½ (1.5/5 stars)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start with the positives. I appreciated the fresh faces portraying Superman, Lois Lane, Lex Luthor, and Jimmy Olsen, particularly in the later scenes and action sequences. The special effects were impressive, and the soundtrack was a highlight. However, that's where the praise ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this film might be the weakest Superman installment to date. Despite a promising cast, the storyline fell short. The inclusion of the Justice League characters like Green Lantern, Mr. Terrific, and Hawkgirl felt forced and detracted from the narrative. It was supposed to be a Superman movie, not a mixed ensemble. Although I'm a bigger fan of Green Lantern than Superman, his role in this film felt misplaced. Nathan Fillion, a fantastic actor known for his sci-fi roles and being a real-life nerd, was miscast. Overall, this movie did not make it to my list of favorite Superman films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more compelling story line and perhaps sticking with Henry Cavill as Superman could have improved the film. While the new actor wasn't terrible, and might have been acceptable had Cavill not already owned the role, he couldn't save the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This product uses the TMDb API but is not endorsed or certified by TMDb.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">tag:michaelmusings.com,2005:Post/14578</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Sun, 14 Dec 2025 05:52:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">n8n</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
