<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scribbles Posts</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Posts from Scribbles.page</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Old Tech, New Posts: My Most Productive Blogging Year Yet</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/post/old-tech-new-posts-my-most-productive-blogging-year-yet</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;figure class="attachment attachment--preview flex-col justify-center attachment--png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="A nostalgic painting of a cozy beachside workspace featuring a vintage CRT monitor displaying the Blogger login screen. The scene includes a classic beige keyboard and mouse, a notebook with handwritten text, a fountain pen, a glass of iced tea, and a vase with dried flowers. Outside the window, two palm trees stand by a serene ocean under a sunny blue sky." class="lightbox__image strip-metadata lightbox__image" decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBK0pDQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--e9157dde3f7f14c6ab61994ac368fb9d8e74a509/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUNHa0NBQVk2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--768aeab7fb7843d85fe5b2b4ba237e06e6ef604f/A%20nostalgic%20workspace.png" srcset="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBK0pDQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--e9157dde3f7f14c6ab61994ac368fb9d8e74a509/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUVHa0NBQXc2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--a18847b6c1cccf2736612f487841b9c550593dc1/A%20nostalgic%20workspace.png 2x"/&gt;
&lt;figcaption class="attachment__caption text-center"&gt;
      Vintage beachside desk with Blogger on screen and ocean view.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have so many ideas running around in my head. I've been blogging more
than ever this year, and it's been my most productive stretch since I
started blogging and building my own website—23 years ago. Although I
don’t think I have many readers, and what I write may not be interesting
enough to spark much interaction, I still enjoy doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when ISPs gave you what seemed like generous personal website
space. My first real ISP was GTE, now Verizon. Before that, I had
dial-up with AOL and those limited minutes, but I mostly used it for
email and a bit of web surfing—usually hunting for information about new
computer games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting DSL from GTE was a game changer. That’s when I really got into
building my own website. It was rudimentary back then, and I probably
overloaded it with information while trying to figure out how FTP
worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny side story about GTE DSL: they were supposed to install it two
weeks earlier than they actually did, but kept putting me off. My
sister-in-law had just started working for them, and after she made a
few calls, they showed up on Labor Day to install it. At the time, I
thought those were the fastest speeds available—and it was expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years later, we switched to Adelphia Cable (now defunct and part
of Comcast, I think). They eventually sold us to Time Warner Cable,
which rebranded the service as Roadrunner. I couldn’t believe how much
faster it was than DSL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of those systems feel archaic compared to what we have today. I now
have a fiber connection with 1 Gbps up and down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I was with GTE/Verizon and building my website, I used
Microsoft FrontPage. I still miss that program to this day. Eventually,
I moved to Blogger. I remember thinking blogging was neat but very
different from building a website. Blogging felt like online
journaling—which it is—and I assumed nobody really cared what I thought.
Honestly, I still think that’s true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with my website, I kept wanting to build all kinds of things. I had
mouse trails, themed layouts for different occasions, and a couple of
photo galleries. I even set it up to take a picture of my desktop and a
webcam snapshot of me at certain times. I used Webcam32 for the webcam
and TechSmith’s Snagit to capture the desktop. I tried to make it my own
portal, piecing together different tools. It probably wasn’t
well-structured, but it all worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Microsoft shut down FrontPage, I was bummed and tried to find
something new. Eventually, I settled on Blogger—which brings me full
circle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I have five websites/blog spaces. I asked a friend who isn’t
technical at all to look at them and tell me which format they liked
best. They really liked Blogger (granted, I’ve customized it with the
help of AI), and my Micro.blog site was a close second. I thought it was
interesting that they preferred my oldest blog. They liked the style,
theme, and layout the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, it's amazing how far things have come—from dial-up and
mouse trails to fiber speeds and AI-assisted customization. Even if
blogging still feels like shouting into the void sometimes, I enjoy the
process. It’s my way of documenting the journey, experimenting with
ideas, and keeping that creative spark alive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;#TechNostalgia #MicroBlogging #ProductiveYear&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">tag:michaelmusings.com,2005:Post/12776</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mon, 21 Jul 2025 23:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
