<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scribbles Posts</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Posts from Scribbles.page</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">My Battle with Subscription Fatigue: Mid-Year Update</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/post/my-battle-with-subscription-fatigue-mid-year-update</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;figure class="attachment attachment--preview flex-col justify-center attachment--png"&gt;
&lt;img alt=" A detailed black and white pencil drawing of a man wearing glasses, sitting at a table with a desktop computer and a glass of iced tea in a Tervis tumbler, thoughtfully reviewing a long receipt. His expression is a mix of slight overwhelm and quiet satisfaction, reflecting the challenge and relief of trimming expenses." class="lightbox__image strip-metadata lightbox__image" decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBN1JIQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--54d7e01ffcdceda2e3a5aca2d997fb1e7df0176d/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUNHa0NBQVk2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--768aeab7fb7843d85fe5b2b4ba237e06e6ef604f/pencil-receipt-glasses-ice-tea.png" srcset="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBN1JIQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--54d7e01ffcdceda2e3a5aca2d997fb1e7df0176d/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUVHa0NBQXc2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--a18847b6c1cccf2736612f487841b9c550593dc1/pencil-receipt-glasses-ice-tea.png 2x"/&gt;
&lt;figcaption class="attachment__caption text-center"&gt;
      Reviewing the long list—trimming expenses brings a mix of relief and challenge.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I figured I’d give an update on my ongoing battle with
subscription fatigue. This is a mid-year check-in, and I might start
doing these quarterly just to keep myself accountable. Over the past few
months, I’ve whittled down my subscription list by several more
services. Most were dropped by choice because of price or lack of use,
while one disappeared on its own when my cell phone plan changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gone by choice are Netflix, SiriusXM, Yahoo! Mail Plus, Mail.com,
Pocket, Peacock, and Protopage. The only one I lost due to my Verizon
Wireless legacy plan was Google Play Pass. Why these services? Mostly,
they became too expensive or the promotional deals ended. For example, I
had the Netflix/Peacock bundle through Verizon Play+. I not only let it
lapse, but Verizon also shut down the entire service. It was a good idea
to have everything in one place, and it could have been even better if
Verizon had used their influence to get better deals from the streaming
services. It would have made things more convenient for people, letting
them manage everything in one place and maybe even get a discount. But
it seems Verizon didn’t want to treat it as a concierge perk for loyal
customers, and they were probably losing more money than it was worth,
even if it worked well as a small loss leader.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Google Play Pass was cut from my Verizon Wireless legacy plan. That
plan is really only worth keeping because of all the perks and bundled
services it used to include. If Verizon ever drops the Disney/Hulu/ESPN+
bundle, or if they keep raising the price until it’s no longer cheaper
than paying for the services separately, I’m out of Verizon postpaid
completely. The main reason I kept that plan was for those extra perks,
but they’re getting harder to justify as they disappear or lose value.
There are other alternatives that would be much cheaper—even if I paid
full price for the Hulu/Disney+ ad-free bundle, I could add HBO Max and
still come out at about the same price I’m currently paying if Verizon
goes any higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Mail Plus is another example. I’m not going to pay for
downgrades. They reduced the storage from 1TB on paid plans to 200GB,
and the free plans are now 20GB. I never used much storage, but that was
one of the main reasons I kept it. I only have one email subscription
going to Yahoo! Mail Plus now. The only reason I haven’t canceled my
account completely is that I still like using their front page and Yahoo
Finance, and I’ve had my Yahoo account since I first got online. But
when they reduced the storage, it just wasn’t worth five dollars a month
to get an ad-free experience. I’ve set it up to use IMAP, so now the
only ads I see are in my email, and it’s usually just a single line and
not a whole page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Protopage, there are a couple of reasons I’m letting it go. They
have actually updated the service a bit in the last year, and honestly,
the fee was reasonable, which is why I was willing to pay it to avoid
ads. But I can get the same effect with a self-hosted solution, and I
haven’t been able to find a privacy policy for Protopage. The lack of
transparency about how they handle user data is the main reason I plan
to let this subscription lapse when the current period ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mail.com is similar. I was late canceling it this year, so I’ll have it
for another year as well. I mainly used it as a cheap backup for years,
but now the free account is perfectly adequate for my needs. Both
Protopage and Mail.com are now set to cancel and won’t be renewed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pocket closed down, but honestly, I was planning to cancel anyway. They
no longer had a good way to export or import your saved items to new
services, which made it less useful. My SiriusXM promotion simply
expired, and they didn’t offer me another one, so that made my decision
easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did reactivate one service: Paramount+. They offered a deal I couldn’t
refuse, so I could catch up on the CBS series I follow. I don’t watch
live TV much these days, and this gives me a way to catch up on shows
I’m invested in, especially the new season of Star Trek: Strange New
Worlds. If they offer me another great annual deal, I might stick with
it, but if not, that’s fine too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it for my update. I need to cut back on expenses, and these are
services I can trim with little consequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;#SubscriptionFatigue #SubscriptionReview #CuttingTheCord&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">tag:michaelmusings.com,2005:Post/12990</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Fri, 08 Aug 2025 13:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
