<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Scribbles Posts</title>
    <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/</link>
    <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Posts from Scribbles.page</description>
    <item>
      <title xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">To Feature Image or Not</title>
      <link xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">https://michaelmusings.com/post/to-feature-image-or-not</link>
      <description xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">&lt;figure class="attachment attachment--preview flex-col justify-center attachment--png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="A laptop and several blank cover cards on a desk, symbolizing choosing a blog’s feature image." class="lightbox__image strip-metadata lightbox__image" decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBeXRPQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--98be0905d5b55e266e9c11140e05889282d20960/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUNHa0NBQVk2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--768aeab7fb7843d85fe5b2b4ba237e06e6ef604f/feature-image-choices-desk-1500x900.png" srcset="https://scribbles.page/rails/active_storage/representations/proxy/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaHBBeXRPQVE9PSIsImV4cCI6bnVsbCwicHVyIjoiYmxvYl9pZCJ9fQ==--98be0905d5b55e266e9c11140e05889282d20960/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsibWVzc2FnZSI6IkJBaDdDRG9MWm05eWJXRjBTU0lJY0c1bkJqb0dSVlE2RkhKbGMybDZaVjkwYjE5c2FXMXBkRnNIYVFJQUVHa0NBQXc2Q25OaGRtVnlld2M2Q25OMGNtbHdWRG9NY1hWaGJHbDBlV2xrIiwiZXhwIjpudWxsLCJwdXIiOiJ2YXJpYXRpb24ifX0=--a18847b6c1cccf2736612f487841b9c550593dc1/feature-image-choices-desk-1500x900.png 2x"/&gt;
&lt;figcaption class="attachment__caption text-center"&gt;
      Choosing a feature image — a quiet desk, a laptop, and blank cards waiting to be filled.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been debating lately whether feature images are a good idea. I
think they are, because I am a very visual person. Even though I often
read materials without pictures, an image grabs my attention and
interest first. I first discovered feature images when I started
learning WordPress. The feature image option was one of the only parts
of WordPress I liked, even though I struggled with the block editor. The
challenge was always finding the right image. Now, with AI, I can
usually get about 95 percent of the way there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have received some pushback about using AI images in my posts (usually
only the feature image is AI). I really do not care much about the
criticism, but some of the feedback has been trollish, and that is not
acceptable. I use AI images the same way I would use WordPress premade
content or any other service’s ready-made material. I am not taking away
a person’s creativity or business, because if I did not use AI or
premade assets, I simply would not use feature images at all. To me,
using AI imagery is a way to be efficient with my resources, especially
since I am already using and paying for the service for other things.
Overall, it is the most cost-effective option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, do you like feature images? Do you use them? What guides your
decision about whether to include them or not? I would love to hear from
you, as long as it is in a respectful way. I will always respond
respectfully, whether I agree with your position or not.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">tag:michaelmusings.com,2005:Post/13305</guid>
      <pubDate xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
